

- © 2091 Gramercy Place Hummelstown, PA17036
- ⊠ dalheidar@gmail.com
- (717) 319 -1779



www.dalia-heidar.com



## TOOLS

- SKETCH FIGMA InVision
- Adobe Suite (Illustrator- Photoshop- After Effects- XD-Dimensions)
- Marval Balsamiq Flinto
- 3DMAX, Autodesk Certificates
- Certified Professional
   "REVIT® Architecture" 2020
   Designer , AUTODESK Corp,
   CERTIFORT 2019 (ID#90066632)
- Sketchup
   Vray
- Microsoft Office
- Freehand, Painting and sketching

## SKILLS

#### **UI Design Skills**

- User Interface Elements ,Patterns& Hierarchy
- Design Principles & Heuristics, Style Guides
- Wireframing (Low, Mid& High Fidelity)
- Building a cohesive brand
- Typography, Icononography
   & Symbol Design
- Mobile App Design
- Design Systems
- Responsive Web App
- Responsive Grids
- Interaction Design & Animation
- Motion Design
- 3D Illustration

### **UX Design Skills**

- User Experience & Design Thinking
- User Psycology
- Information Architecture
- User Testing User Research
- Interpeting & Analyzing
- Business Requirements
- Personas & User Stories
- User Flows and Journeys
- Web Design (In Progress)

## Certificates & Studies

STARTAD (Venture Launchpad/ Entrepreneurship Program), New York University - Abu Dhabi (NYU -AD), (2017)

Leadership Development Certificates ,Faculty of Leadership Development Center (FLDC), UA

- Effective Presentation
   Skills
- Conference Organization
  &Writing Scientific Papers
  & Int. Publication.

## Publications & Honors

- Co-Author "Encyclopedia of Modern & Contemporary Architecture & their Pioneers", Volume1, 2 & 3
- Ranked 2nd of Class in Interior Arch. B.Sc. Program, Faculty of Fine Arts.

## Languages

- Fluent English
- Fluent Arabic
- French (Fair)
- HTML · CSSJAVASCRIPT (In Progress)

## MY PROFILE

Freelance UX/UI designer with a background in Interior Architecture, Digital Design & Research (PhD). Experienced in Visual Design, User Interactions, research & analysis, and enjoy working within a collaborative team. Working on Front-End Developer Certification.

### EDUCATION

Front End Development Certificate, Mentored Program with Training CareerFoundry -Germany (In Progress) also Harvard University - CS50 Course.

**UI Immersion Certificate** - UX Coursework , Mentored Program with Training CareerFoundry -Germany

PhD in Design

Faculty of Fine Arts, University of Alexandria

MSc. in Design,

Faculty of Fine Arts , University of Alexandria

**BSc. in Interior Architectural Design**, with Honor Degree Faculty of Fine Arts, University of Alexandria

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### April 2020 to Present

## FreeLance UI / UX Designer

AD4X4 LOGBOOK App., Abu Dhabi 4X4 Offroad Club, UAE

A Logbook App for an Offroad Club - will be launched soon
Conducted User Testing on Club Members - User Experience
Design & User Interface Design - Designed iOS & Android Native
App & Responsive Web App.

Worked with Club Developer

THE GRAZZING ARCHITECT, E-Commerce App., VA, USA

Flower and Foodies small Business (*In Progress*)
UX & UI DESIGN for a Responsive App.

### CAREERFOUNDRY PROJECTS, Germany

Full Projects with Professional UI/UX Mentors and One-on-One Tutoring & Supervision through out the International Certified Program.

Travel App

BestBeats - Music App

EL COOK - Recipe Sharing App (Responsive Web App).

AD4X4 LOGBOOK- iOS & Android App Versions

OnChat-Messaging App Noted - Note taking App

DALI DZIGN - E-Commerce App (Furniture & Design)

#### 2010 to April 2020

## FreeLance Interior Architectural Designer

- Executed various Interior Design projects (Residential & Commercial Design), Mood Boards, Meeting Clients, Space Plans, Elevations,
   2D Illustrations, 3D Presentations, Perspectives, Wall Treatments,
   Furniture & Accessories.
- Conducted Workshops, Logo Designs, Murals and Paintings.

#### 2009 to Present

## Interior Architecture Design Lecturer

2010 - Present (on leave) - Tenured Lecturer, Department of Interior Architectural Design, Faculty of Fine Arts, University of Alexandria.

<u>Spring 2009</u> - Adjunct Professor, Department of Interior Design, Faculty of Science & Engineering, Abu Dhabi University, Abu Dhabi, UAE

- Managed Junior Designers (Students and Demonstrators)
   Construct a Schedule for Groups till final handoff & Attending Exibitions..
- Monitored Development of groups from Brainstorming, Sketches,
- Analysis & Research Lecturing on Interior Design Trends
   & Techniques.
- Prepared Students for Plans, Elevations, Perspectives for Presenting Projects.

## Previously

## Designer and Marketing / Sales Engineer.

## Egyptian Belgium company for Aluminum Doors & Windows

Sales, Marketing & Design Units- Discussing the design with.
the customer and the manufacturing engineers to reach final
design that could be manufactured according to the factory
capacity and capabilities after preparation of digital designs.